おはよう
Good morning.
もう ちゃんと座って食べなさい 行儀悪い
My goodness... Sit properly while you eat, won't you?
That's bad manners.
「今朝もいろいろなニュースがあったわけですが」
There's a number of news items to discuss this morning,
「私がピックアップしたのはこのニュース」
but this is the headline that caught my attention.
「『声優アズキュン 奇跡の純愛 ラジオで激白』」
"The miraculous pure love of voice actress, Azukyun"
Listeners Cry
Over her
Purity of
Love
Fans of Azukyun
shed farewell
tears over her
marriage
announcement
Her
boyfriend,
the popular
manga
artist
Mashiro
Moritaka
(24),
also called
live on
the phone
Revelation on the Radio
and her confession over the radio.
「中学の時に交わした『夢が叶うまで会わない』という約束を」
Pick Up
The promise they made in middle school not to meet until their dreams were granted—
きれいなお嬢さんじゃないか
She's a pretty girl, isn't she?
し 仕事行ってくる
I-I'm going to work.
随分早いわね まだ8時よ
That's pretty early for you.
It's only 8 o'clock.
いろいろあって少し遅れ気味だから
I have to do some stuff first, so I'll be late if I don't go now.
ごちそうさま
Thanks for breakfast.
最高
Moritaka.
お母さん反対しないから
I'm not against it.
何を
Against what?
美保さんとの結婚よ
Your marriage with Miho.
か 母さん
M-Mom!
わしも反対なんかせんよ
I won't oppose it either.
お おじいちゃんまでからかわないでよ
N-Not you too, Grandpa!
Don't tease me!
からかっとりゃせんよ
I'm not.
お前はもう立派に働いとる一人前の男だからな
You've become a real man, a proper hardworking member of society.
結婚 か
Marriage, huh?
yu
me
Dreams, dreams, dreams, dreams
ka
na
e
ru
ta
bi
ko
wa
re
te
yu
ku
me
As soon as I reach my goals, it all falls through again
na
ze
so
re
de
mo
ma
ta
So why do I run...
bo
ku
wa
sa
ga
su
ha
shi
ri
tsu
zu
ke
ru
...and search in spite of that?
hi
sa
shi
bu
ri
ni
de
atta
We met after such a long time
"
fu
n
i
ki
ka
watta?"
"Has the mood changed for us?"
tsu
ki
hi
wa
na
ga
re
ta
da
rou
So much time has passed
"
a
no
ko
ro
no
ho
u
ga
ta
no
shi
so
u
"
"It seemed like more fun back then"
ta
ku
sa
n
na
ku
shi
ta
We've lost so much
so
n
na
ko
to
wa
ki
zu
i
te
ru
n
da
I already know that, though
sa
ke
bi
tsu
zu
ke
ro
mo
ga
ki
tsu
zu
ke
ro
Don't stop screaming, don't stop struggling
da
re
no
ta
me
ni
na
n
ka
mou
i
da
rou?
You've done enough for others
ma
da
tsu
ta
e
i
ko
to
ga
a
ru
ma
da
I still, still have something I haven't told you yet
yu
me
no
sa
ki
ni
wa
yu
me
shi
ka
na
i
Beyond each of my dreams lies yet another dream
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)出品 仅供交流学习之用 禁止用于商业用途
---诸神字幕组---
台本: 共由         翻译: 新人&poopy       繁化: 烨语
校对：绫女       时间轴：Color
Mic and Script
あたしもびっくりしたわよ
I was surprised too.
朝テレビつけたら取り上げられちゃっててさ
It was all over the news when I turned on the TV this morning.
しかも「清い交際」でしょ
And they called it "a pure relationship," right?
ちょっと清すぎる気もするけどな
Too pure, maybe.
そうよね
You're right.
サイコー ちょっと
Hey, Saikou.
何だよ テレビの話なら もう
What?! Enough about the news already—
そうじゃないって
That's not it.
キャーッ 美保3位に上がってる
This Month's Favorite Voice Actor Ranking
Voice actor
FAN MORE
Votes
Namba Kana
Ohtsuki Nanami
Azuki Miho
Majima Saki
Tanaka Mikan
Naka Yoshiko
Miho's rank went up!
一時はどうなるかと思ったけど 昨日のラジオのおかげだな
I was worried for a while there, but it looks
like last night's broadcast had a positive effect.
うん きっとそう 美保の誠意がちゃんと伝わったんだよ
Yeah, that must be it!
Miho managed to get her sincerity across to everyone.
それに今回の件 一般にも知られたって事はでかいよな
Also, it's good for us that normal
people now know about this story.
亜豆が「REVERSI」のヒロインになっても
Even if she does get picked for the part in Reversi,
今朝のテレビみたいに応援してくれるだろうし
they'll support her, just like they did on the news today.
Yup!
でも それって実力で役を取ったって事になるのかな
Can we really say that she got the job with her own skill if that happens, though?
ちゃんとオーディションもやるし 問題ないだろ
She's taking the audition, so no problem there.
まあ 話題性に人気
Ohtsuki Nanami
Azuki Miho
Majima Saki
Tanaka Mikan
But based on her popularity and
skills, and the buzz surrounding her,
もちろん実力から言っても亜豆に間違いないだろうけど
Azuki's bound to get the part.
考えすぎだって
You're overthinking this.
「REVERSI」亜豆美保のおかげですごい注目度ですよ
Thanks to Azuki Miho, Reversi has an
amazing amount of attention on it right now.
Production and Conference room
Drawing
Post Production and Photographing
これでいいスタートダッシュが切れそうです
We should be able to hit the ground running.
小中さん
Konaka.
はい
Yes?
Satoru,
you've changed.
You used
to be more kind.
You just
went along
with it?
Ashirogi Mutou
ヒロインの「菜保」もオーディションで一番ふさわしいと
We're going to hold auditions for the role of Naho
and choose the most suitable voice actress, correct?
私たちが判断した声優にやってもらいたいんだよね
もちろんオーディションはやりますよ
Of course we're having auditions!
でも 今の流れだとほぼ決まりでしょう
But at this rate, it's practically been decided already.
REVERSI
storyboard
よし 原稿OK
All right, your manuscript looks good.
ありがとうございます
Thanks.
それから「REVERSI」1・2巻ともまた重版かかったぞ
Weekly Shounen Jack
And also, both Volume 1 and 2 of
Reversi have another print on the way.
Weekly Shounen Jack
やった
Great!
これで1巻当たり83万部
With this, you're selling about 830,000 copies per volume.
「ZOMBIE☆GUN」の105万部までもう一息だ
Just one more push until you reach
Zombie Gun's number of 1.05 million!
はい
Right!
ほんと アニメ化が決まると注目されるんですね
You really do get more attention
when you have an upcoming anime.
Anime Adaptation
Confirmed!
Ashirogi Mutou
それもあるが この間のラジオがいい方向で話題になった
There's that, but recent radio broadcasts have brought about a lot of positive attention.
ラジオって 亜豆の
By radio broadcasts, were you talking about Azuki's?
Yeah.
どうも君たちは 逆境に立たされれば立たされるほど
It seems that there's something in you two that
makes you stronger with each hardship you face.
それを力にしてしまう何かを持っているようだ
そんな大げさな
You're exaggerating.
本当に大した2人
These two really are something else.
いや 亜豆美保の強さもだ
No, Azuki's strength is here, too.
この子たちなら 夢を叶え進んでいくに違いない
They'll definitely move forward and achieve their dreams.
ですよね 服部さん
Right, Hattori?
ど どうしたんですか
Wh-What's wrong?
いや この勢いなら「ジャック」の真の看板になるのも夢じゃない そう思ってな
Uh, nothing.
At this rate, becoming Jack's flagship may not be just a dream.
That's what I was thinking.
ほんとですか
Really?
Yeah.
真の看板か
The true flagship, huh?
俺たちにも やっと追い風が吹いてきたな
Finally things are going our way!
そうだな
I'll say.
そう 今は追い風なんだ
Right. Everything's going our way now,
だから亜豆も 必ず菜保役を取ってくれる
so Azuki will definitely get the role of Naho.
正々堂々と オーディションで
Fair and square, by audition.
Anime Adaptation
Confirmed!
Congrats!
Ashirogi Mutou
それじゃあ 僕はこれからアニメのスタッフと打ち合わせがあるから
Well, I have to attend a meeting with the anime staff.
こんな時間からですか
At this hour?
何でも 早急に決めたい事があるとかで
Apparently there's something urgent they need to make a decision on.
早急ですか 何かトラブルでも
Urgent?
Is there some kind of problem?
そんな大げさなものじゃないさ
It's not that big of a deal.
一応終わったら連絡するよ
I'll call you as soon as it's over.
というご提案なのですが
And that's our proposal.
随分思い切った提案ですね
It's a pretty drastic one.
江原監督が可能ならやらせてもらえないかと
Director Ehara has insisted that you let us proceed with this if at all possible.
しかし この場の人間だけでは
B-But we can't decide on this without Ashirogi's input.
亜城木先生にも聞いてみませんと
それはもちろんです
Of course.
服部 段取りは任せる
Hattori, I'll leave the arrangements for that in your hands.
Huh?!
菜保役を公開オーディションで
A public audition for the role of Naho?
はい 菜保役に限りテレビとネットでの公開オーディションにしたいと
Yes.
We'd like to hold a public audition for the role of Naho on the TV and Internet.
でも 何でそんな事を
But why?
私が提案しました
I proposed it.
まず こちらで候補を20人くらいに絞り込みます
First, we will narrow down the
candidates to 20 possible choices.
そして 本番のオーディションをテレビとネットで同時配信し
We'll then hold the public audition,
broadcasting it live on TV and the Internet simultaneously,
見てもらった人に1人1票というルールで投票してもらう事で
and allow viewers to have one vote each in a poll that will decide who will play Naho.
菜保役を決めるんです
駄目だ そのやり方じゃ亜豆は確実に落ちる
They can't do that!
Azuki definitely won't get the role that way!
何で
Why?
ネットだと まだ批判的な意見が多いんだよ
There are still many critical opinions of her on the Internet.
熱狂的な亜豆美保ファンなら なおさら票を投じないと考えた方がいい
That's even more true of the hardcore Azuki fans. They won't vote for her.
僕もここまでする必要があるかは疑問だ
I also have my doubts as to whether this is necessary.
実力で見てもらえないって事か
You mean, they won't vote based on her abilities.
いえ だからこそやるべきなんです
No, that's precisely why we must do this.
私もあのラジオを聴き お二人の姿勢に感動を覚えました
Upon hearing that radio broadcast, I too was touched by your mindset.
だからこそ 言わせて頂きたい
That's why I must say this:
このままでは亜豆美保がたとえ実力で役を取ったとしても
In this situation, even if Azuki Miho
wins the role through her skill alone,
どうせ形だけのオーディションと思われるでしょう
in most people's minds, the
audition will merely be a formality.
そんな
That can't be!
そうか
I see.
ずっと引っ掛かっていたのはこれだったんだ
This is what has been bothering me.
風向きが変わったからといって ただそれに乗っていたら
If we simply ride the changing tide of public opinion...
真城君 私
Mashiro, I...
オーディション受かってみせます
will pass the audition.
それでも 僕は
Even so, I...
誰よりも亜豆美保に菜保役をやってほしいと思っています
There's nobody who wants Azuki Miho to play the role of Naho more than me.
それも実力で取ってほしいと その気持ちだって誰よりも
And there's nothing I want more than for her to get the role by her skills alone.
この公開オーディションで実力がはっきりするというのなら
If you say that skill will be the only thing judged at these public auditions,
僕は賛成します
then I'll agree to it.
I'm telling you, there's a possibility they won't vote on skill alone.
だ だから これだと実力で選ばれない可能性が
そうだ 真城君 じっくり考えた方がいい
That's right, Mashiro. You should think carefully about this.
たとえどんな結果になったとしても
No matter the result,
亜豆がコネで役を取ったと言われるよりいい
it's still better than people saying that
Azuki got the role through her connections.
彼女より人気 実力がある声優さんがいたとしても
Though there may be voice actresses
who surpass her in popularity and skill,
亜豆美保はその上をいきます
Azuki will rise above them.
いや 上をいかなければ 菜保役を演じる資格はありません
No... If she doesn't rise above them, then she doesn't have what it takes to play Naho!
公開オーディションだって
They said it's a public audition.
どうせ亜豆美保ってやつで決まってんだろ
Azuki Miho's going to win no matter what, anyway.
News
flash!
Media
Volume 4 "Turn"
Anime
starting
this fall!
Minadori Naho's
voice actress is...
Up to the open auditions!
そうよね 大人の事情っていろいろあるもんね
Yeah, there are some complicated situations going on with that.
相変わらず荒れてんな アズキュンスレ
Anonymous is desperate
Naho's voice actress will be decided in an open audition, right?
You betrayed us, Azuki Miho, you deserve punishment!
I really want to see how this will turn out.
Anonymous is desperate
They're busy flaming each other in the Azukyun thread, like usual.
俺「大月奈々観」に投票するから関係ないもんねえ
Who cares? I'm gonna vote for Ohtsuki Nanami anyway.
「ナナミン」推しですか
Oh, you're a Nanamin fan?
やっぱ投票は愛だよな
It's just a big popularity contest anyway.
どうしたの 難しい顔して
What are you frowning at?
わあ 何これ
What's this?
REVERSI Minadori Naho Voice Actress Poll
Valid votes
Option
st
nd
rd
th
Graph
Nanba Kana
Ohtsuki Nanami
Tanaka Mikan
Majima Saki
Azuki Miho
Arijima Aki
Votes
REVERSI Minadori Naho Voice Actress Poll
美保が 5位
Miho's in 5th...
REVERSI Minadori Naho Voice Actress Poll
いや これは声優ファンが遊びでやってる模擬投票
It's just a fake poll put together by
voice actress fans for the heck of it.
REVERSI Minadori Naho Voice Actress Poll
本番の投票とは関係ないから
It's not related to the real poll at all.
何だ
Oh, good.
って こんな紛らわしいもの見るのやめなさい
Hey, don't look at such misleading stuff!
はい すみません
Okay. I'm sorry.
「みんなも 私と サトルと同じように考え」
If everyone thought and acted the same as I... as Satoru does—
ちゃんと返事を聞いてからドアを開けてよね
Hey, wait until I say you can come in.
ごめん お姉
Sorry, Sis.
全然悪いと思ってないくせに
You don't look sorry at all.
どうしたの
What is it?
こんなやり取りもあと何回できるのかなって思っちゃって
I was just wondering how many more times I'll be able to come in like this.
な 何よ急に まだヒロイン役も決まってないのに
Wh-What are you saying all of a sudden? It's not like I've gotten the role yet.
ここで決めてもらわないと
This is when it counts.
学業の合格のお守りなんだけど
This is a good luck charm for success in
studying, but it'll work for this too, right?
いいよね
ありがとう
Thanks.
で ご飯です
Oh, and it's dinner time.
はーい トンカツに カツサンド
Tada! For "winning"(katsu), we have tonkatsu, tonkatsu sandwich, katsudon, katsuo, and a big chickwin!
カツ丼 カツオに 大きな鳥でビックトリー
それにパスするパスタでーす
And some pasta for "passing"!
もう こんなに験を担いじゃって
Geez, Mom. You're so superstitious.
パパ 帰ってきても食べきれないよ
And even when Dad gets home,
there's no way we can eat all this.
ごめんね
Sorry.
全然悪いと思ってないでしょう
You don't look sorry at all.
お母さんこんな事しかできないけど
This is all I can do for you.
明日は頑張って
Do your best tomorrow.
お母さん
Mom...
なあ サイコー
Hey, Saikou.
Hmm?
中学生がマンガ家や声優になるのを夢みて
For a middle schooler to dream of becoming a manga artist or a voice actress,
実際にその夢を叶えるのって すげー 難しい事なんだろうな
and actually make that a reality is a really hard thing to do, don't you think?
ん まあ 何だよ急に
Yeah, I guess.
What's this all about?
いや そう考えるとサイコーと亜豆の夢って
Well, when you think of it that way, the dream you and Azuki share is impossibly hard to achieve.
気が遠くなるほど難しい事だったはずだろ
明日 亜豆はその夢のマイクの前に立つ
Tomorrow, Azuki will stand before that microphone of dreams.
ほんと すげーよ
It's really amazing.
夢のマイクの前か
The microphone of dreams, huh?
そう考えるとここまで来ただけでも幸せだって思わなきゃいけないよな
According to that line of thought, we should be happy just to have gotten as far as we have.
マンガ家 声優 どれだけの人が目指して諦めていってるか
A manga artist, a voice actress.
How many people have wanted to become either one, and have given up already?
何だよ 亜豆が落ちてもヘコむなって言ってるように聞こえるぞ
What's with that?
It sounds like you're trying to tell me not to get depressed if she fails.
違うって
That's not it.
俺も亜豆が受かると信じてる
I believe she'll get the role.
その夢が叶うのがどんだけすごいかの確認だって
I'm just reaffirming how amazing it will be to achieve that dream.
ほんと すげーんだよ
It's really amazing.
でさ そのあとが最高でさ
And like, what comes after is the best.
何だよ じらしやがって
Are you teasing me or something?
アズキュン 来た
It's Azukyun!
アズキュン 頑張って
Do your best, Azukyun!
コネのくせに よく来られたな
I can't believe you actually showed up, what with all your connections!
俺たちを裏切りやがって
アズキュン ファイト
You betrayed us!
Go, Azukyun!
Don't mind them.
気にするな
はい
Right.
Open auditions
For actresses
Satoru.
おはようございます
Good morning.
亜豆さんよく来られたわね
I can't believe she showed up.
私なら絶対来ない
I wouldn't have.
やっぱり原作者の意見で決まるのよね
It's going to be decided by the author, anyway.
そうでしょう 恋人なんだし
Yeah, she's his girlfriend, after all.
なんか ずるーい
What? That's pretty unfair.
あ 美保ちゃ わぁ
Miho!
いたたた
大丈夫ですか 南波さん
Are you okay, Namba?
いつも かっこ悪いとこばっか見られてるね
You always catch me at my worst.
でも 今日のオーディションは絶対に負けないからね
But I definitely won't lose to you in today's audition!
はい よろしくお願いします
Yes. I'm looking forward to it.
うん お互い頑張ろう
Yeah, let's both do our best.
おはようございます 郷田さん
Good morning, Ms. Gouda!
おはようございます
Good morning.
おはよう
Hello.
ああ あなたが亜豆美保さん
Oh, you are Azuki Miho?
は はい
Yes.
今回 こんな舞台を作ってくれた事には感謝しています
I am grateful to you for creating such a stage.
同じ声を当てるにしてもこれだけの話題の中
All I have to do is read my lines like normal, and I can win the role with all eyes on me!
役をつかむ事ができるんですから
そのとおりですね
That's exactly right.
あら 奈々観ちゃん
Oh, Nanami.
お久しぶりです また ご一緒できて光栄です
It's been a while. I'm honored to work with you again.
私もよ
Same here.
でも まさか菜保役を郷田さんも受けられるとは思いませんでした
But I never thought you'd try out for the role of Naho.
私も選考通るとは思わなかったわ
I was also surprised to be chosen as one of the candidates.
まだ必要とされてるって事かしら
I suppose it means I'm still needed around here.
そうですね 郷田さんにはまだ頑張って頂きませんと
That's right. You have to keep at it, Ms. Gouda.
南波さんも今日はよろしくね
Good to see you again, Namba.
よろしくお願いします
And you.
皆さん 今日は正々堂々と頑張りましょうね
Now everyone, let's play fair and have a good audition, okay?
はい
Yes!
菜保役はあなたが決める
You decide who plays Naho!
『REVERSI』公開オーディション
Open Auditions
for the role of Minadori Naho!
The Reversi public audition!
さあ いよいよ始まります
It's finally starting!
Open Auditions
for the role of Minadori Naho!
はい この秋に放送スタートのアニメ『REVERSI』の女優を
Yes. In this program, you'll be able to vote for
始まっちゃったね
It's begun.
the actress who will play the role of Naho in the anime Reversi, which will start this fall.
みんなさんの投票で決めてしまおうという番組です
投票の方法は後ほどお知らせします
Later on, we'll tell you how to vote.
それでは早速 といきたいところですが
Now, let's begin—Or so I would like to say,
その前に この作品がどういった内容なのか
but first, please watch this informational video that will outline the plot of the manga.
分かりやすくまとめたVTRをご用意しましたので ご覧下さい
And that's how it's going to work.
Open auditions
For actresses
説明は以上です
あの ちょっといいでしょうか
Um, can I ask a question?
はい
中継 始まってるぞ 急げ
Yes?
The broadcast is about to start. Hurry up!
はい
Uh, yes!
3番までの方 スタジオに移動して下さい
Would the first three candidates head to the studio?
他の方は呼ばれるまで ここでお待ち下さい
The rest of you, please wait until you're called.
1番 田中美菅です よろしくお願いします
Number one, Tanaka Mika.
Thank you for your consideration.
また こんな時間まで1人で教室に
Once again, you're all by yourself in the classroom this late?
やっぱかわいいだけじゃないのね
へっ『ヴァイセ』って 何
So she's not just cute.
What is "Weiss"?
ありがとうございました
Thank you.
Editorial Department
Shounen Jack
Jack SQ
X Jack
田中さん お疲れさまです
Thank you, Tanaka.
"Oh, sorry"
"Huh? Satoru? No idea."
aaaaa"Oh, then  he probably went home by him
"Satoru... Staying alone in the classroom till late again?"
"Eh? What is 'Weiss'?"
すがすがしい演技でしたね
It was a refreshing performance.
はい さすがプロだなって感心しちゃいました
Yes. I could really tell that she was a pro.
On Air
Oh, Namba is up next.
次は南波か
二番 南波加奈です 水鳥菜保やらせていただきます
Number 2, Namba Kana. I'll be
playing the role of Minadori Naho.
若手の中では一番人気と聞いてます
I hear she's the most popular one
among the younger voice actresses.
実力も結構ありますよ
よろしくお願いします
Thank you for your consideration.
And she's pretty skilled to boot.
サトル おはよー
Good morning, Satoru!
昨日の数学の宿題分からない所あるんだけど
There's some parts of yesterday's math homework that I don't understand.
さすが人気NO.1ね
サトルって優しいよね ノート見せてくれるだけじゃなくて
She's not the most popular for nothing.
Satoru, you're so nice. Not only do you let me borrow your notes,
Yeah.
いつも ちゃんと分かるまで教えてくれるから
but you also explain things until I understand them.
ええ サトル 知らないけど
Huh? Satoru? I don't know.
ああ じゃあ 1人で帰ったのかも
Oh, then he probably went home by himself.
さすが郷田さん 抜群ですね
That's Gouda for you. She's excellent.
Satoru, you're all by yourself in the classroom again?
そうですね
Yes.
どうしちゃったの
What's wrong? You won't go home with your friends anymore.
友達とも帰らない
私とも帰ってくれない
Or with me.
それに最近 サトル 変わった
And lately, you've changed.
前はもっと人に優しかった
You used to be more kind.
この人 上手
This lady is good.
さすがに みんなうまいわね
Everyone is really good.
If everyone thought and acted the same as I... as Satoru does,
美保 大丈夫かな
Will Miho be okay?
大丈夫に決まってるだろ な
Of course she will!
Right?
the world would be a much better place.
Yeah.
熱の入った演技 ありがとうございました
Thank you for a passionate performance.
皆さん うますぎて 誰か一人なんて選べないんですよ
They're all really good. It's so hard to pick just one.
真城君
Mashiro...
Do we really have to wait till
our dream comes true?
いつまで
Will you...
いつまで待っててくれますか
Will you keep waiting for me?
今は真城君が私を待っててくれてる
Now, Mashiro is the one waiting for me.
次 亜豆美保さん よろしくお願いします
Next, Azuki Miho.
Your turn.
はい
Okay.
これから演じるひと言ひと言が夢につながる言葉
Each and every word I'm about to perform
are words leading to my dream.
7番 亜豆美保です
Number seven, Azuki Miho.
「水鳥菜保」を演じさせて頂きます よろしくお願いします
I will be acting the part of Minadori Naho.
Thank you for your consideration.
彼女 台本持ってない
She doesn't have the script.
Then, please go ahead and begin.
多分パフォーマンスのつもりでしょう
It must be because she intends to move around while she acts.
サトル おはよう
Good morning, Satoru!
昨日の数学の宿題分からない所あるんだけど
There's some parts of yesterday's math homework that I don't understand.
サトルって優しいよね
Satoru, you're so nice. Not only do you let me borrow your notes,
ノート見せてくれるだけじゃなくて
いつもちゃんと分かるまで教えてくれるから
but you also explain things until I understand them.
すごい爽やか
She's really refreshing!
それに 今まで聞いた事ない美保の声
And this is a voice I've never heard Miho use before.
Yeah!
アッハハ サトル ますます顔 赤くなってるよ
Your face is getting redder, Satoru.
ごめん ごめん
I'm sorry. Thanks for teaching me this.
教えてくれて ありがとう
「アズキュン上手じゃん 素人にはわからないかもしれないけど」
Azukyun is really good!
Anon in live chat
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Amateurs may not pick up on it.
「お前プロなのかよ」
Are you a pro or something?
Anon in live chat
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Are you a pro or something?
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Are you a pro or something?
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Are you a pro or something?
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Are you a pro or something?
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Are you a pro or something?
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Are you a pro or something?
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Are you a pro or something?
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Are you a pro or something?
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Are you a pro or something?
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Are you a pro or something?
Azukyun is really good.
But amateurs may not pick up on it.
Anon in live chat
Are you a pro or something?
「俺 素人だけど いいと思う」
I'm an amateur, but I think she's good.
「素人にも分かるじゃん」
See, even amateurs can tell.
「いや ナナミンやカナリンには勝てねーよ」
No, it'd be near impossible to win against Nanamin.
え サトル
On Air
Huh? Satoru? I don't know.
亜豆美保は いいですね
知らないけど
Azuki Miho is good.
じゃあ 一人で帰ったのかも
まあ 悪くはないです
Oh, then he probably went home by himself.
She's not bad.
サトル また こんな時間まで1人で教室に
Satoru, once again you're all by
yourself in the classroom this late?
え シュバルツって何
Huh?
What is "Schwarz"?
セリフ間違えましたね
That line was wrong.
「『シュバルツ』って言った」
Anon in live chat
What if she forgets her lines?
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
She said "Schwarz"!
Anon in live chat
What if she forgets her lines?
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
Anon in live chat
What if she forgets her lines?
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
Anon in live chat
What if she forgets her lines?
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
Anon in live chat
What if she forgets her lines?
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
What if she forgets her lines?
Anon in live chat
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
She said "Schwarz"!
Anon in live chat
What if she forgets her lines?
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
「えっ 違うの」
Anon in live chat
What if she forgets her lines?
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
That's wrong?
Anon in live chat
What if she forgets her lines?
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
What if she forgets her lines?
Anon in live chat
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
She said "Schwarz"!
Anon in live chat
What if she forgets her lines?
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
What if she forgets her lines?
Anon in live chat
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
She said "Schwarz"!
Anon in live chat
That's wrong?
What if she forgets her lines?
Anon in live chat
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
She said "Schwarz"!
Anon in live chat
That's wrong?
What if she forgets her lines?
Anon in live chat
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
She said "Schwarz"!
Anon in live chat
That's wrong?
What if she forgets her lines?
Anon in live chat
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
She said "Schwarz"!
Anon in live chat
That's wrong?
「『シュバルツ』じゃなくて『ヴァイセ』」
Anon in live chat
What if she forgets her lines?
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
That's wrong?
Anon in live chat
What if she forgets her lines?
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
That's wrong?
It's not Schwarz, it's "Weiss"!
Anon in live chat
What if she forgets her lines?
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
That's wrong?
Anon in live chat
What if she forgets her lines?
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
That's wrong?
Anon in live chat
It's supposed to be "Weiss"!
What if she forgets her lines?
Anon in live chat
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
She said "Schwarz"!
Anon in live chat
That's wrong?
It's supposed to be "Weiss"!
Anon in live chat
What if she forgets her lines?
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
That's wrong?
Anon in live chat
It's supposed to be "Weiss"!
What if she forgets her lines?
Anon in live chat
Damn she's cute, too bad she has a boyfriend.
She said "Schwarz"!
Anon in live chat
That's wrong?
It's supposed to be "Weiss"!
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
That's wrong?
Anon in live chat
It's supposed to be "Weiss"!
「夢破れました」
There go her dreams.
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
That's wrong?
Anon in live chat
It's supposed to be "Weiss"!
She said "Schwarz"!
Anon in live chat
That's wrong?
It's supposed to be "Weiss"!
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
That's wrong?
Anon in live chat
It's supposed to be "Weiss"!
She said "Schwarz"!
Anon in live chat
That's wrong?
It's supposed to be "Weiss"!
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
That's wrong?
Anon in live chat
It's supposed to be "Weiss"!
There go her dreams.
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
That's wrong?
Anon in live chat
It's supposed to be "Weiss"!
There go her dreams.
Anon in live chat
She said "Schwarz"!
That's wrong?
Anon in live chat
It's supposed to be "Weiss"!
There go her dreams.
Anon in live chat
That's wrong?
It's supposed to be "Weiss"!
Anon in live chat
There go her dreams.
たまに意味の分からない事言うし
Sometimes you say things I don't understand.
どうしちゃったの
What's wrong?
友達とも帰らない
You won't go home with your friends anymore.
私とも帰ってくれない
Or with me.
それに最近
And lately...
サトル変わった
You've changed.
前はもっと人に優しかった
You used to be more kind.
合わせていた どういう意味
You just went along with it?
What do you mean?
みんなも私とサトルと同じように考え 行動すれば
If everyone thought and acted the same as I... as Satoru does,
すばらしい世界になる
then the world would be a better place.
まだ間に合う やり直せる
It's not too late.
We can remake it.
普通とか常識とか そんなものは
"Normalcy" and "common sense" are just shackles imposed by the people who run the world.
今 世界を動かしてる人の押しつけ
ありがとうございました
Thank you.
Th-That was some splendid acting.
すばらしい演技でしたね
はい
Yes.
セリフの間違いは投票に影響するでしょうね
The mistake in the lines will have an impact on the vote.
監督
Director!
どうしました 小中さん
What's wrong, Konaka?
ちょっと問題が
We have a problem.
問題
A problem?
美保の演技すごかった
Miho's acting was great!
今までの中じゃダントツだよね
It was way better than everyone else's!
中継の途中ですが 監督の江原さんよりコメントがあります
Yeah!
We're sorry to interrupt the broadcast,
but Director Ehara has something to say.
では 監督 お願いします
Go ahead, Director.
先ほどの亜豆美保さんの演技について 少し説明させて頂きます
I would like to explain something
about Azuki Miho's performance, which we just heard.
亜豆さんは台本上のセリフで「ヴァイセ」となっているところを
In the script where "Weiss" was originally
used, she said the name "Schwarz" instead.
「シュバルツ」と演技しました
What? Miho made a mistake?
美保 間違えちゃったの
しかし これは私どものミスでした
However, this was our own mistake.
ミス
Their mistake?
私どもは『週刊少年ジャック』本誌をもとに今回の台本を作りました
We made the script based off of the magazine, Weekly Shounen Jack.
しかし 問題の部分は本誌が誤植であり
But in this section, there was a misprint by the magazine,
コミックスでは『ヴァイセ』から『シュバルツ』に訂正されているという連絡を
and it was corrected from "Weiss" to
"Schwarz" in the compilation volume.
先ほど編集部の方から頂きました
The editing department just informed us of this.
なるほど 原作をちゃんと続けて読めば
Indeed, having "Weiss" there would seem strange for anyone who read the manga closely.
「シュバルツ」でなければおかしい
ですので 亜豆さんは原作を尊重しての演技をしたという事で
Since Azuki followed the original work in her performance, this will not count as a mistake.
間違えとはいたしません
よかった
That's such a relief.
もちろん『ヴァイセ』と演技された方も間違いではありません
Of course, the people who used "Weiss" will not be penalized.
しかし これから演技される方は
However, we would prefer it if those who have yet to perform would use "Schwarz" instead.
できれば正しい『シュバルツ』の方でお願いします
台本のミスに気付いた事が重要なんじゃない
The fact that they noticed a mistake in the script isn't the issue here.
そんな事より 亜豆美保のあの演技
What's more important here was Azuki Miho's acting.
それでは オーディションを再開いたします
We will now resume the audition.
以上で 20名すべての演技が終了しました
The 20 candidates have all finished.
終わった
It's over.
なんか疲れたね
That was tiring.
それでは皆さんお待たせしました
And now, what you've all been waiting for.
これより 投票受け付けを開始させて頂きます
We will now begin accepting votes.
期限は今から1時間
You have one hour from now to enter your votes.
テレビをご覧の方はリモコンの『ｄボタン』を
For those watching on TV, press the D button on your remote.
美保ちゃんすごかった
Miho was really good.
でも 私だって負けてないはず
But I don't think I did any worse than her.
亜豆美保 侮っていたわ
Azuki Miho... I underestimated her.
Huh? Is that true?
それ ほんと
声 大きいって
You're too loud!
うん 亜豆さんの台本書き込みも読んだ跡もなかった
Azuki Miho's script copy didn't have comments
written on it. It looked like it hadn't been read at all.
きっと亜城木先生にいろいろ聞いてたんだよ
I'm sure Ashirogi told her what part it was going to be ahead of time.
だから「ヴァイセ」の所も「シュバルツ」って
That's why she knew it was "Schwarz" instead of "Weiss"—
あなたたちにはあの亜豆さんの演技や姿勢がそんな安っぽいものに見えたんですか
Do you really think Azuki's performance and attitude was that cheap?
きっと彼女は 原作の「何ページの菜保のセリフを」と言えば
Most probably, if you gave her any page number from the manga,
さっき見せたレベルで演じてくれるはずです
she could perform Naho's lines from it at the level of performance you saw.
分かりますね
Do you understand?
はい
Yes.
でも 勝負は勝負です
However, a competition is a competition.
私は誰にも負ける気はありません
I don't intend to lose to anyone.
お待たせしました
It's now time!
応募総数 19万2728票
We received 191,728 total votes!
いよいよ発表か
The announcement at last.
たくさんの投票 ありがとうございました
Thank you for all your votes.
この中から 今日1人のヒロインが誕生します
A heroine will be born from one of you.
果たして 誰がそのヒロイン役を手にしたのでしょうか
Who has won the role of the heroine?
それでは 発表します
And now, we will make the announcement.
アニメ『REVERSI』の『水鳥菜保』役を勝ち取ったのは
The winner of the role of Minadori Naho, the heroine of Reversi, is...
この方です どうぞ
This person!
Naka Yoshiko
Ohtsuki Nanami
Azuki Miho
Kitani Mai
やったー
She did it!
圧倒的票数で
Azuki
Miko
With an overwhelming lead, Azuki Miho lands the role!
亜豆美保さんに決定しましたー
わあ お姉ちゃん やったー
She did it!
これで 結婚できる
Now she can get married!
それでは 亜豆さんステージの方へお願いします
Now then Azuki, please come up to the stage.
よかった よかったよ
I'm so glad! I'm so glad!
サイコーも黙ってないで もっと喜べよ なあ サイコー
Saikou, don't be so quiet!
Celebrate a little!
サイコー
Saikou!
固まってる
He's frozen stiff.
真城 大丈夫
Mashiro, are you okay?
大丈夫 よかった
I'm okay.
I'm so glad.
Yeah.
ほんとに よかった
I'm so glad.
皆さん
Everyone.
おめでとう 亜豆さん
Congratulations, Azuki.
悔しいですけど あれだけの演技をされたら 何も言えません
I hate to say it, but after that performance you gave I hold no grudge for losing against you.
そんな
That's...
今日 勝ち取った役は紛れもなく あなたが実力で手に入れたものです
Without a doubt, you have won the role
today based on the strength of your skill.
その事をしっかり自覚して下さい
Please believe that.
菜保役 頑張ってね
Good luck with the Naho role.
美保ちゃん おめでとう
Congrats, Miho!
菜保役 私たちの分までしっかりね
Work hard on our behalf, too.
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
do
u
shi
te
da
ro...
i
tsu
mo
so
u
sa
Why, I wonder?
chi
ka
zu
ku
ta
bi
ka
ra
ma
wa
ri
no
yu
me
Whenever I am close to fulfilling my goals, all effort becomes fruitless
ma
e
wo
mu
i
te
shi
ga
mi
tsu
i
te
sou
su
ko
shi
zu
tsu
We walk ahead, hold each other, and with little things
ya
ku
so
no
a
ba
sho
he
to
sa
e
ai
na
ga
ra
we support each other to reach what we promised
ji
shi
n
ga
ta
ri
na
i
to
ki
wa
mu
ne
ni
te
wo
a
te
When we lack confidence, we put a hand to our heart
bo
ku
ra
ga
tsu
zu
t
ta
pe
e
ji
yo
mi
ka
e
so
u
and reread the pages we assembled into a story
kyo
u
ma
de
so
shi
te
a
su
he
to
tsu
zu
i
te
yu
ku
no
sa
They lead up to today and continue into the morrow
ta
i
se
tsu
na
yu
me
ga
ka
na
u
so
no
hi
ma
de
We will always be ourselves
a
ri
no
ma
bo
ku
ra
de
zu
tto...
until the day that our dreams come true
Next Time
Preview
さあ いよいよラストスタートだ
It's finally the last spurt!
自分たちが選んだ道なら悔いはない
I have no regrets about the path we've chosen.
次回 あり方と終わり方
Next time: How it Should be and How it Ends
How It Should Be and
How It Ends
俺たちは 夢と共に駆け抜ける
We'll run through it all with our dreams!